Register of The Militant Photographic Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- International (Non-United States) Scenes.
  - Laos
    - Maps (Folder 37: 31)
    - U.S. military intervention (Folder 37: 32)
    - Pathet Lao (Folder 37: 33)
  - Lebanon (Box 38)
    - Maps (Folder 38: 1)
    - General (Folder 38: 2)
    - Civil war, 1976 (Folder 38: 3)
    - Israeli invasion, 1982 (Folder 38: 4)
    - Civil war, 1990s (Folder 38: 5)
    - Palestinians (Folder 38: 6)
    - U.S. troops (Folder 38: 7)
    - European troops (Folder 38: 8)
  - Liberia (Folder 38: 9)
  - Libya
    - Maps and general (Folder 38: 10)
    - Mass demonstrations (Folder 38: 11)
    - U.S. bomb strikes (Folder 38: 12)
    - Individuals (Folder 38: 13)
  - Macedonia (Folder 38: 14)
  - Malaysia (Folder 38: 15)
  - Mali (Folder 38: 16)
  - Martinique (Folder 38: 17)
  - Mauritania (Folder 38: 18)
  - Mauritius (Folder 38: 19)
  - Mexico
    - Historical background
      - General (Folder 38: 20)
      - Individuals (Folder 38: 21)
    - Repression, pre-1968 (Folder 38: 22)
    - Events of 1968 (Folder 38: 23)
    - Detained and disappeared, 1968-1970s (Folder 38: 24)
    - Repression and student protests, 1970s (Folder 38: 25)
    - Ibarra de Piedra family, 1970s (Folder 38: 26)
    - Earthquake, 1986 (Folder 38: 27)
    - Workers and industry, 1980s (Folder 38: 28)
    - Student conference on NAFTA, Guadalajara, 1992 (Folder 38: 29)
    - General
      - 1995 (Folder 38: 30)
      - 1996 (Folder 38: 31)
      - 1990s (Folder 38: 32)
    - Protests (Folder 38: 33)
    - Peasants and rural protests (Folder 38: 34)
    - Revueltas, José (Folder 38: 35)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 38: 36)
    - Individuals (Folder 38: 37)
  - Middle East
    - Maps (Folder 38: 38)
    - Politicians (Folder 38: 39)
  - Mongolia (Folder 38: 40)
  - Morocco
    - Maps and general (Folder 38: 41)
    - Individuals (Folder 38: 42)
  - Mozambique
    - Maps and general (Folder 38: 43)
    - War for independence (Folder 38: 44)
    - Rightist guerrillas and war destruction (Folder 38: 45)
    - Individuals (Folder 38: 46)
  - Namibia (Box 39)
    - Maps (Folder 39: 1)
    - General (Folder 39: 2)
    - Individuals (Folder 39: 3)
  - Nepal (Folder 39: 4)
    - Netherlands
    - General (Folder 39: 5)
    - Protests (Folder 39: 6)
    - Individuals (Folder 39: 7)
  - New Caledonia
    - Maps and general (Folder 39: 8)
    - Struggle for independence (Folder 39: 9)
    - Individuals (Folder 39: 10)
  - New Zealand
    - General (Folder 39: 11)
    - Labor (Folder 39: 12)
    - Maori rights (Folder 39: 13)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 39: 14)
    - Individuals (Folder 39: 15)
  - Nicaragua
    - Maps (Folder 39: 16)
    - U.S. interventions, 19th century to 1930s (Folder 39: 17)
    - Sandino, Augusto, and Sandino resistance, 1920s and 1930s (Folder 39: 18)
    - Earthquake, 1972 (Folder 39: 19)
    - Somoza, Anastasio, 1970s (Folder 39: 20)
    - Anti-Somoza struggle, 1970s (Folder 39: 21)
    - Sandinista period, 1979-1990
      - Children (Folder 39: 22)
      - Comités de Defensa Sandinista (Folder 39: 23)
      - Contra war
        - Contra war (Folder 39: 24)
        - Contra weapons (Folder 39: 25)
        - Draft evaders (Folder 39: 26)
        - Soldiers and militia (Sandinista) (Folder 39: 27)
        - U.S. intervention (Box-folder 40: 1)
          (including Eugene Hasenfus)
        - War destruction (Folder 40: 2)
      - Culture (Folder 40: 3)
      - Education and literacy campaign (Folder 40: 4)
      - Housing (Folder 40: 5)
      - Internal opposition
        - La Prensa (Folder 40: 6)
        - Rightists (Folder 40: 7)
      - International solidarity
        - Foreign leaders in Nicaragua (Folder 40: 8)
        - International brigadistas in Nicaragua (Folder 40: 9)
        - Ben Linder protests, 1987 (Folder 40: 10)
        - Militant tours (Folder 40: 11)
        - Nicaraguan solidarity with other struggles (Folder 40: 12)
        - Pathfinder Press Managua Bureau (Folder 40: 13)
        - U.S. supporters in Nicaragua (Folder 40: 14)
      - Labor
        - Anti-Sandinista unions (Folder 40: 15)
        - Demonstrations and union meetings (Folder 40: 16)
        - Factories, mines, mills and workers (Folder 40: 17)
        - Strikes (Folder 40: 18)
      - Markets (Folder 40: 19)
      - Mass demonstrations
        - 1979-1980 (Folder 40: 20)
        - 1981-1982 (Folder 40: 21)
        - 1983 (Folder 40: 22)
        - 1984 (Folder 40: 23)
          (including election campaign)
        - 1985-1986 (Folder 40: 24)
        - 1987-1989 (Folder 40: 25)
          (including peace accords and amnesty demonstrations)
      - Medical care (Box-folder 41: 1)
      - Peasants and farm workers
        - Asociación de Trabajadores del Campo (Folder 41: 2)
        - Harvest brigades (Folder 41: 3)
        - Land reform (Folder 41: 4)
        - Unión Nacional de Agricultores y Ganaderos (Folder 41: 5)
      - Prisons (Folder 41: 6)
      - Women (Folder 41: 7)
        (including Asociación de Mujeres Nicaragüenses Luisa Amanda Espinoza)
      - Atlantic Coast region
        - General (Folder 41: 8)
        - Autonomy process (Folder 41: 9)
        - Bluefields (Folder 41: 10)
        - Garifonas (Folder 41: 11)
        - Misatan Assembly (Folder 41: 12)
        - Miskitos (Folder 41: 13-14)
          (including resettlement)
        - Puerto Cabezas (Folder 41: 15)
        - Rama (Folder 41: 16)
        - Sumus (Folder 41: 17)
        - Individuals (Folder 41: 18)
      - Arce, Bayardo (Folder 41: 19)
      - Borge, Tomás (Folder 41: 20)
      - Carrión, Luis (Folder 41: 21)
      - Ortega, Daniel (Box-folder 42: 1)
      - Ortega, Daniel, with others (Folder 42: 2)
      - Ortega, Humberto (Folder 42: 3)
      - Ramírez, Sergio (Folder 42: 4)
      - Tirado, Victor (Folder 42: 5)
      - Wheelock, Jaime (Folder 42: 6)
      - Other Sandinista leaders (Folder 42: 7)
      - Sandinista leaders in groups (Folder 42: 8)
      - JS-19 (youth) leaders (Folder 42: 9)
      - Military and police officers (Folder 42: 10)
      - Obando y Bravo, Cardinal (Folder 42: 11)
      - Contra leaders (Folder 42: 12)
      - Other individuals (Folder 42: 13)
    - Post-Sandinista period, 1990s
      - General (Folder 42: 14)
      - Elections, 1990 (Folder 42: 15)
      - Chamorro, Violeta, and cabinet (Folder 42: 16)
      - Defacement of mural (Folder 42: 17)
      - Demonstrations (Folder 42: 18)
      - Peasants and farm workers (Folder 42: 19)
      - Strikes (Folder 42: 20)
      - Sao Paulo Forum, Managua, 1992 (Folder 42: 21)
  - Niger (Folder 42: 22)
  - Nigeria
    - Maps and general (Folder 42: 23)
    - Individuals (Folder 42: 24)
  - Norway (Folder 42: 25)
  - Oman
    - Maps (Folder 42: 26)
    - Guerrillas (Folder 42: 27)
    - Individuals (Folder 42: 28)
  - Pacific Ocean region (Folder 42: 29)
  - Pakistan
    - Maps and general (Folder 42: 30)
    - Protests (Folder 42: 31)
    - Individuals (Folder 42: 32)
  - Palau (Folder 42: 33)
  - Panama
    - Maps (Folder 42: 34)
    - Historical background (Folder 42: 35)
      (including Panama Canal)
    - U.S. forces (Folder 42: 36)
    - Canal sovereignty struggle (Folder 42: 37)
    - Canal Treaty signing, 1978 (Folder 42: 38)
    - General, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 42: 39)
    - U.S. invasion, 1989 (Folder 42: 40)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 42: 41)
    - Individuals (Folder 42: 42)
  - Peru (Box 43)
    - Maps (Folder 43: 1)
    - General (Folder 43: 2)
    - Military repression (Folder 43: 3)
    - Protests (Folder 43: 4)
    - Peasant and rural struggles (Folder 43: 5)
    - Blanco, Hugo (Folder 43: 6)
    - Blanco peasant movement (Folder 43: 7)
    - Blanco supporters (Folder 43: 8)
    - Anti-Vietnam War protests (Folder 43: 9)
    - Individuals (Folder 43: 10)
  - Philippines
    - Maps (Folder 43: 11)
    - General (Folder 43: 12)
    - Marcos, Ferdinand (Folder 43: 13)
    - Military and vigilante repression (Folder 43: 14)
    - Social conditions (Folder 43: 15)
    - Workers and peasants (Folder 43: 16)
    - Protests
      - Marcos regime (Folder 43: 17)
      - Post-Marcos period (Folder 43: 18)
    - Individuals (Folder 43: 19)
  - Poland
    - Historical background (Folder 43: 20)
    - Communist Party and government officials (Folder 43: 21)
    - Catholic Church figures (Folder 43: 22)
    - Dissidents (Folder 43: 23)
    - Walesa, Lech (Folder 43: 24)
    - Solidarnosc strikes and protests (Folder 43: 25)
    - Post-1989 protests (Folder 43: 26)
  - Portugal
    - Maps (Folder 43: 27)
    - Revolution, 1974-1975 (Folder 43: 28)
    - Carvalho, Otelo Saraiva de (Folder 43: 29)
    - Fourth Internationalists (Folder 43: 30)
    - Individuals (Folder 43: 31)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 44)
    - General (Folder 44: 1)
    - Individuals (Folder 44: 2)
  - Romania
    - Maps (Folder 44: 3)
    - General (Folder 44: 4)
    - Ceausescu, Nicolae (Folder 44: 5)
  - Russia
    (including Soviet Union)
    - Historical background (Folder 44: 6)
    - General (Folder 44: 7-9)
    - Economic and social conditions (Folder 44: 10)
    - Dissidents (Folder 44: 11)
    - Coup attempt, 1991 (Folder 44: 12)
    - Individuals (Folder 44: 13-14)
  - Rwanda (Folder 44: 15)
  - St. Lucia (Folder 44: 16)
  - St. Vincent (Folder 44: 17)
  - Saudi Arabia
    - Maps (Folder 44: 18)
    - General (Folder 44: 19)
    - Military (Folder 44: 20)
    - Fahd, King (Folder 44: 21)
  - Senegal—Maps (Folder 44: 22)
  - Seychelles
    - Maps (Folder 44: 23)
    - General (Folder 44: 24)
    - Individuals (Folder 44: 25)
  - Sierra Leone (Folder 44: 26)
  - Singapore (Folder 44: 27)
  - Somalia
    - Maps (Folder 44: 28)
    - Ethiopian war, 1970s (Folder 44: 29)
    - U.S. intervention, 1992 (Folder 44: 30)
  - South Africa (Box 45)
    - Maps (Folder 45: 1)
    - General, 1950s and 1960s (Folder 45: 2)
    - Social conditions
      - 1970s (Folder 45: 3)
      - 1980s (Folder 45: 4)
      - 1990 (Folder 45: 5)
      - 1991 (Folder 45: 6)
      - 1992 (Folder 45: 7)
      - 1993 (Folder 45: 8)
      - 1994 (Folder 45: 9)
    - Political actions
      - 1970s (Folder 45: 10)
      - 1980s (Folder 45: 11)
      - 1990 (Folder 45: 12)
      - 1991 (Folder 45: 13)
      - 1992 (Folder 45: 14)
      - 1993 (Folder 45: 15)
      - 1994 (Folder 45: 16)
    - Police and military, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 45: 17)
    - Ultrarightists, 1991 (Folder 45: 18)
    - General (Box 46)
      - 1994 (Folder 46: 1)
      - 1995 (Folder 46: 2)
      - 1996 (Folder 46: 3)
    - Mandela, Nelson
      - 1950s and 1960s (Folder 46: 4)
      - 1990 (Folder 46: 5)
      - 1991 (Folder 46: 6)
      - 1992 (Folder 46: 7)
      - 1993 (Folder 46: 8)
      - 1994 (Folder 46: 9)
    - Buthelezi, Gatsha (Folder 46: 10)
    - Klerk, F. W. de (Folder 46: 11)
    - Individuals (anti-apartheid figures)
      - A-F (Folder 46: 12)
      - G-L (Folder 46: 13)
      - M (Folder 46: 14)
      - N-S (Folder 46: 15)
      - T-Z (Folder 46: 16)
      - Contact sheets (Folder 46: 17)
    - Contact sheets (Box 47)
      - 1990 (Folder 47: 1)
      - 1991 (Folder 47: 2)
      - 1993 (Folder 47: 3)
      - 1994 (Folder 47: 4)
  - Spain
    - Maps (Folder 47: 5)
    - Historical background (Folder 47: 6)
    - General (Folder 47: 7)
    - Protests, post-1975 (Folder 47: 8)
    - Franco, Francisco (Folder 47: 9)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 10)
  - Sri Lanka
    - Maps (Folder 47: 11)
    - Historical background (Folder 47: 12)
    - Revolt and repression, 1971 (Folder 47: 13)
    - Tamil struggle (Folder 47: 14)
    - Tampoe, Bala (Folder 47: 15)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 16)
  - Sudan
    - Maps (Folder 47: 17)
    - al-Numeiri, Gaafar (Folder 47: 18)
  - Surinam—Maps (Folder 47: 19)
  - Sweden
    - General (Folder 47: 20)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 21)
  - Switzerland (Folder 47: 22)
  - Syria
    - Maps (Folder 47: 23)
    - Assad, Hafez (Folder 47: 24)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 25)
  - Taiwan
    - Maps (Folder 47: 26)
    - Chiang, Ching-kuo (Folder 47: 27)
    - Chiang, Kai-shek (Folder 47: 28)
  - Tanzania
    - General (Folder 47: 29)
    - Nyerere, Julius (Folder 47: 30)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 31)
  - Thailand
    - Maps (Folder 47: 32)
    - General (Folder 47: 33)
    - Protests (Folder 47: 34)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 35)
  - Trinidad (Folder 47: 36)
  - Tunisia
    - Maps (Folder 47: 37)
    - Protests (Folder 47: 38)
  - Turkey
    - Maps (Folder 47: 39)
    - General (Folder 47: 40)
    - Repression (Folder 47: 41)
    - Strikes and protests (Folder 47: 42)
    - Kurds (Folder 47: 43)
    - Individuals (Folder 47: 44)
  - Uganda (Box 48)
    - Maps (Folder 48: 1)
    - Repression (Folder 48: 2)
    - Individuals (Folder 48: 3)
  - Ukraine (Folder 48: 4)
  - United Arab Emirates—Maps (Folder 48: 5)
  - Uruguay
    - Maps (Folder 48: 6)
    - General (Folder 48: 7)
  - Vanuatu (Folder 48: 8)
  - Vatican
    - Pius XII, Pope (Folder 48: 9)
    - John Paul II, Pope (Folder 48: 10)
  - Venezuela
    - Bravo, Douglas (Folder 48: 11)
    - Individuals (Folder 48: 12)
  - Vietnam
    - Maps (Folder 48: 13)
    - Individuals (Folder 48: 14-15)
      (including Ho Chi Minh)
    - War period, 1946-1954 (Folder 48: 16)
    - Geneva Conference, 1954 (Folder 48: 17)
    - War period, 1961-1975
      - Protests against Saigon government (Folder 48: 18)
      - Political prisoners in South Vietnam (Folder 48: 19)
      - War victims (Folder 48: 20)
      - North Vietnamese/Viet Cong forces (Folder 48: 21-22)
      - Viet Cong-administered zones (Folder 48: 23)
      - Tet offensive, 1968 (Folder 48: 24)
      - U.S. warplanes (Folder 48: 25)
      - U.S. troops (Folder 48: 26)
      - U.S. troops with captives (Folder 48: 27)
      - Communist victory, 1975 (Folder 48: 28)
    - Post-1975 period
      - General (Folder 48: 29)
      - War damage (Folder 48: 30)
      - Chinese invasion damage, 1979 (Folder 48: 31)
      - Refugees (Folder 48: 32)
      - Farmers and agriculture (Folder 48: 33)
      - Health, education and housing (Folder 48: 34)
      - Markets (Folder 48: 35)
      - Workers and industry (Folder 48: 36)
      - Rightists (Folder 48: 37)
  - Western Sahara (Folder 48: 38)
  - Yugoslavia
    - General (Folder 48: 39)
    - Refugees and war victims, 1992 (Folder 48: 40)
    - War damage, 1992 (Folder 48: 41)
    - Protests, 1992 (Folder 48: 42)
    - Militant reporting trip contact sheets, 1992 (Folder 48: 43)
    - Kosovo—Militant reporting trip contact sheets, 1998 (Folder 48: 44)
  - Zambia (Folder 48: 45)
  - Zimbabwe (Folder 48: 46)
  - Miscellany
    - Marx, Karl, and Friedrich Engels (Folder 48: 47)
    - Second International figures (Folder 48: 48)
    - United Nations (Folder 48: 49)
    - World Federation of Democratic Youth events (Folder 48: 50)
    - Anti-Vietnam War demonstrations (Canada, Europe, Australia) (Folder 48: 51)
    - Anti-Gulf War demonstrations, 1990-1991 (Folder 48: 52)
      (Canada, Puerto Rico, Europe, Australia, New Zealand)
    - Irish solidarity demonstrations (Great Britain, Australia) (Folder 48: 53)